Akinbowale Faluta

Product Manager

└ 09051313461 ⊠ falutawale@gmail.com **in** https://cutt.ly/2kh7Bfm

2 Aborishade Close, Lawanson, Surulere, Lagos

Professional Summary

A strategic, goal-oriented Product Manager with experience delivering multi-faceted insights, strategies, and tactics surrounding multi-channel product management, technology, branding, sales, and new business development. Highly regarded for expertise in identifying product opportunities and translating trends into on-brand product solutions that effectively communicate company vision and values. A distinguished record of orchestrating a customer-focused approach to marketing, sales, and business innovation that delivers predictable and profitable results. Provide full lifecycle product management, roadmap development expertise while earning a solid reputation for complex problem resolution, professionalism, innovation, and productivity.

Professional Experience

03/2020 – present Lagos, Nigeria

Lead Product Manager

Nairabet

- Conducted 500+ customer interviews for product feedback, with suggested improvements leading to a 95.6% customer satisfaction level
- Collaborating with product marketing and developed a marketing initiative that resulted in a 2% response rate from new punters.
- Managed customer relationship by providing timely product information and sales support, hence contributing to increased sales by 15%.
- Development of Product Definition for the Nairabet Betting Terminal. Development of user manual on the betting terminal which reduced customer complaints by 50%.

09/2018 – 02/2020 Lagos, Nigeria

Financial Product Analyst

Pagatech

- Reduced implementation cost by 37%. Eliminated several manual processes by collaborating with the Product Team.
- Worked with various teams in addressing challenging Agent expectations during platform conversion which increased the number of POS users by 3%.
- Introduced the Finance team to the Agile way of getting the job done which resulted in a 100% increase in the team's productivity.
- Reconciliation of Transactions done on the Paga Mobile app including Bill Payments, Deposit to Bank, airtime Purchase, and Card Transactions which reduced bad debt by 30%.

05/2017 - 08/2018 Lagos, Nigeria

Reconciliation Officer

Union Bank of Nigeria

- Ensure timely and accurate reconciliation for all Franchise, Nigerian Customs Service (NCS), and FIRS accounts in order to reduce company loss by 10%.
- Identification of entry errors for necessary reversals which results in optimal efficiency.
- Identification, analysis, and reporting of fraudulent or unauthorized transactions which has been of benefit to the bank and reduced risk by 90%.
- Ensure that the Proof balance is the same as FCUBS GL Balance.

08/2015 - 09/2016 Lagos, Nigeria

Brand Specialist

OLX Nigeria

- Communicating new initiatives and key issues to prospective customers led to increasing in sales by 50% every month.
- · Verifying a customer's identification, responding to customer's changing needs and expectations minimizes the level of fraud on the organization's site.
- Activation of new customers and re-activation of dormant customers amounting to 100 new users a week.
- Giving support to customers via phone calls, email, and online chats to enable them to find the website and app user friendly. This led to a 38% increase in site visitors.

Education

07/2019 - present Lagos, Nigeria

M.Sc. Management University of Lagos

09/2009 - 06/2013 Ogun, Nigeria

B.Sc. Banking and Finance

Babcock University

CGPA: 4.1

Certificates

Agile Product Management 2 Utiva Product School **Software Processes** and Agile Practices 🗷 Cousera Certified Courses

How to build Digital Products □ **Product School**

Content Marketing

Certified 2 **HubSpot Academy** **Brand and Product** Management 2 Coursera Course Certificates

Fundamental Steps of Product Management

Ø Udemy **Enterprise Online** Training [2] Enterprise Development

Stanbic IBTC

Centre - Pan-Atlantic University

Skills

- Design Thinking
- User Research (market and competitive)
- Agile methodologies (Scrum)
- Analyzing product metrics for growth and troubleshooting
- Wireframing and Prototyping with Figma
- Collaborating with crossfunctional teams

Reference

Available on Request